

Hi, my name is

Jonas Eriksson

... and I am a FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

070 420 01 75



Havsörnsvägen 85, 123 53 Farsta



ionaseriksson84@amail.com



www.mynameisjonas.dev



PROFILE

Jonas is a fullstack web developer with 7 years of professional experience. He particularly enjoys doing frontend development and JavaScript, though comfortable with backend and API development as well.

Jonas is a social person who thrives in a strong team, but he is also full of initiative and drive - and will quickly learn new processes, environments and technologies on his own. Regardless of project, Jonas always has a professional attitude and a clear focus on delivering results.

SKILLS

Frameworks: React, Svelte, Vue, AngularJS, Django, Node, jQuery

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Java, SQL, Jinja2

Databases: postgres, MySQL, DB2

Tooling: Webpack, Rollup, Gulp, Grunt, Yarn, Karma, Jasmine, pytest

Version handling & CM: Git, CVS, SVN, JIRA, TFS

Other: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Ansible, Vagrant, Jenkins, Linux, REST, GraphQL, Scrum, Web Design, Project

Management

EXPERIENCE

• FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER / Reason Studios

October 2017 — present

Jonas currently works as a fullstack web developer in the Sales & Marcom department of Reason Studios (formerly Propellerhead Software)

- Quickly got up to speed in new languages for the position Python & Django.
- Technical responsibility for web shop generating 75% of the yearly \$120M revenue
- True full stack development all the way from database to React frontend.
- Extensively involved in infrastructure and devops.

Methods & tools: React, Django, jQuery, JavaScript, Python, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Java, SQL, Jinja2, postgres, MySQL, Webpack, pytest, Git, JIRA, AWS, Ansible, Vagrant, Jenkins, Linux, REST

• CONSULTANT / HiQ

August 2014 — October 2017

Worked as a consultant in primarily frontend positions in the organizations listed below.

• FULLSTACK DEVELOPER / Swedish Police

June 2016 — October 2017

Jonas was the lead frontend developer for internal tools ported from COBOL systems to modern web-based applications. In addition to frontend development Jonas has also done significant backend development.

- · Delivered two applications into production far ahead of schedule
- Introduced frontend build systems and frontend testing into the team.

Methods & tools: AngularJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, Java, JBoss, Git, REST, Swagger, Gulp, Karma, Jasmine, Maven

• FRONTEND DEVELOPER / Midroc

October 2014 — June 2016

For the most part Jonas worked as solo or primary front end developer. In addition to implementation, Jonas has also had extensive input on UX elements and design. Moreover, Jonas has been responsible for introducting many new APIs and technologies such as the Sharepoint API, Microsoft ADAL.js and Microsoft Graph API to the organization.

- New Intranet based on Sharepoint REST API and AngularJS frontend. Starting point for 1 100 employees and 70 000 visits per month.
- Campaign portal celebrating the client's 20-year anniversary.
- Modern responsive portals for project reporting used by in-field technicians and PMs/administrators.
- Performance and UX improvements for time reporting portal.

Methods & tools: AngularJS, Azure AD, Bower, CAML, CSS3, Git, Git-TF, GruntJS, HTML5, Jasmine, JavaScript, jQuery, Karma, LESS, Microsoft ADAL.js, Microsoft Graph API, Node, npm, OAuth2, REST, SASS, SCRUM, Sharepoint Online, Sharepoint REST API, TFS, Yammer, Yeoman

• CONSULTANT / Capgemini

February 2012 — August 2014

Worked as a consultant in the projects listed below.

• JAVA DEVELOPER / VPC / Euroclear

February 2012 — August 2014

Jonas joined this project as a fresh graduate and within a year had advanced to main developer of the Java-based applications. He was also assigned to the "core" team consisting of 7 consultants out of the 25 employee strong team.

- Estimation, analysis, debugging, documentation for incidents and change requests.
- · Held various project management duties; time-plans, team briefings and client meetings
- Co-responsible for review of new hires, including training and code reviews.

Methods & tools: Apache ANT, Apache Commons, Apache POI, Apache Tomcat, CSS, CVS, DB2 SQL, Efecte, HTML, IBM Message Broker, IBM Tivoli Access Manager, WebSEAL, iText, Java, Java EE, Java Server Faces, JavaMail, JavaScript, JIRA, JMS, LDAP, MyFaces, Spring, WebSphere Application Server

Planning, executing and reviewing a successful and highly appreciated customer event consisting of three camps throughout each year for clients and fellow employees.

Responsibility for annual budget of SEK 150 000 with an audience of CxO level participants.

• MASTER'S THESIS / Configura

August 2011 — December 2011

Jonas wrote his Master's Thesis for the Linköping-based software company Configura. Configura develops 3D software used for space-planning and layouts in rooms and industrial environments. Jonas quickly learned the various advantages and problem areas of the software and development processes. The finished thesis contained both an analysis of the current situation as well as suggestions for future improvements.

EDUCATION

• M.Sc. Industrial Engineering and Management (Intl, Japanese)

2006 — 2011

The Institute of Technology at Linköping University

- Computer Science, which entails courses in programming (Java, Python, SQL and more), computer architecture as well as larger project-based advanced software engineering courses.
- · Industrial Marketing, focusing on the marketing function, and strategic management and positioning.

• Exchange Studies

2008 — 2009

明治大学 / Meiji University, Tokyo

Exchange student programme as part of the masters degree. All courses were given in Japanese, and consisted of business and management courses.

• Foundation year in Japanology

2005 — 2006

The Institute of Technology at Linköping University

Preparation for International Programme - Japanese language studies, and to a lesser extent courses on Japanese culture and society.

 High School - Natural Science Programme Stångådalens Gymnasium, Vimmerby 2000 - 2003